A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of Civilian Defense, 1940-1945.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Office of Civilian Defense,
1940-1945.
The Library of Virginia
22499
Virginia. Office of Civilian Defense.
XX cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Arranged by type of record and chronologically or alphabettically thereunder.
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and other protected information is considered confidential and restricted from public access for 75 years. It may be necessary for an archivist to review any unprocessed, modern record collections (those collections less than 75 years old) that may contain confidential information before the records can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies of records can be made for patrons. If you are planning to use these records, please contact Archives Reference Services for more details before planning your research trip.
Acquisition Information
Accession 22499 was transferred by the Virginia World War II History Commission on 8/10/1950
Historical Information
Following the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor and the entry of the United States into World War II, the federal and state governments took measures to protect the citizenry against enemy attack. The General Assembly passed a civilian defense act on February 11, 1942, establishing the Office of Civilian Defense to organize a system of self-protection for the state and its residents.
The office established a statewide network of observation posts for volunteer aircraft spotters and created emergency medical and evacuation procedures. Civilian morale was raised by the encouragement of victory gardens and salvage drives and by providing assistance to servicemen and their families. With the defeat of Germany and Japan in 1945 the need for the office came to an end. On November 19, 1945, Governor Colgate Darden, Jr., issued an executive order abolishing the office effective January 1, 1946.
Scope and Content
XX
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1942-1945
Series II. Correspondence with localities, 1942-1945
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1942-1945., Extent: 10.15 cubic feet (29 boxes). (Box 1-29)
  This series is housed in 29 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent or by company name. These files consist of copies of the outgoing correspondence of the Director of the Office of Civilian Defense, J. H. Wyse, as well as correspondence from Wyse by others in the office, including J. Linwood Rice (Assistant to the Coordinator), Mary V. Marks (Supervisor of Civilian Mobilization), James F. Nicholas (Supervisor of Negro Civilian Defense Activities), and John Howard (Chief Air Raid Precautions, State Plant Coordinator), among others. Files were kept separately for 1942 and for 1943-1945 (bulk 1943-1944) and that arrangement is reflected in this series. Correspondence, 1943-1945, also includes a notation on each letter as to where copies of the letters are also filed in the Subject Files series. The majority of the correspondence is with local civilian defense council (CDC) representatives and state and federal officials.
  - Correspondence, 1942.
    - A, 1942 December. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A, 1942 November. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A, 1942 September-October. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A, 1942 August. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A, 1942 July. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A, 1942 June. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A, 1942 April-May. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A, 1942 March. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A, 1942 January-February. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Abbitt, George, Jr. (Appomattox County Civilian Defense), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Abbitt, J. R. (Division of Grounds and Buildings), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 December. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 November. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 October. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 September. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 August. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 July. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 June. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 May. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Adams, Rowland K., Judge (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942 April. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Agnew, Ella (W.P.A.), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Allen-Morrison Sign Company, 1942. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Alper, Saul (Wythe County Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Ambler, Gordon B., Hon. (Richmond Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ancell, W. Guy (Hopewell Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Anderson, C. R., Dr. (Winchester Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Anderson, J. A., Gen. (Highway Dept.), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Arthur, Elizabeth (Winchester Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arthur, J. Pinkney (Winchester Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Arthur, R. W. (Wythe County Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Aylor, Eugene (Madison County Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Ayres, B. Drummond (Accomack County Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - B, 1942 December. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B, 1942 November. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - B, 1942 October. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - B, 1942 September. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - B, 1942 August. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - B, 1942 July. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - B, 1942 June. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - B, 1942 April-May. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - B, 1942 March. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - B, 1942 February. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - B, 1942 January. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bagby, B. B., Dr. (Northumberland County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bain, W. W., Dr. (Nottoway County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Baldock, Ashby W. (Henry County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bane, Frank, Hon. (Council of State Governments, 1942. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Barber, Columbus S. (Stafford County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Barclay, R. C. (Portsmouth City Manager), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Barr, John E., Lt. Col. (First Interceptor Command), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Barr, Taylor L. (Winchester Fire Dept.), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Barrett, Henry S., Col. (Maryland Council of Defense), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Barton, Robert T., Jr., Col. (Richmond-Petersburg-Hopewell Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bassett, J. E. (Henry County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Battle, M. S., Col. (State Police and Safety), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Baumes, Harold I. (League of Virginia Municipalities), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bedwell, B. F. (Dinwiddie County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Benchoff, Robert J. (Shenandoah County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bennett, Maurice E., Jr. (Norfolk CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bickers, R. W. (Greene County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Biggins, J. C. (Newport News CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bird, Paul E. (Smyth County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Blair, W. L. (Pittsylvania County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Blake, Marion G. (Richmond-Petersburg-Hopewell Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Bland, Loucille (Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bland, S. Otis, Hon. (House of Representatives) 1942. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Blanford, Paul S. (Powhatan County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Bobbitt, H. I. (Federal Bureau of Investigation), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bolles, Lemuel, Col. (Metropolitan Area Civilian Defense), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Bolton, R. J. (Montgomery County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Booth, A. A. (Danville CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Booth, Gardner L. (Northern Virginia Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Booth, R. A. (Prince George County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Booth, William H., Lt. Comm. (Middlesex County CDC), 1942. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Borland, Charles B., Col. (Norfolk CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bosang, J. G. (Pulaski County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bottom, Raymond B., Maj. (Naval Operating Base), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bowman, John Fox (Fauquier County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bradford, J. H. (Division of the Budget), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Breed, Semour W. (Goochland County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Brent, Katherine R. (Powhatan County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bright, Fulmer J., Brig. Gen. (State Office of Price Administration), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Brill, Edmund (Treasury Dept. - War Saving), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Brown, James W. (State Dept. of Education), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bruner, Francis D.(Prince George Councy CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bryant, W. S., Capt. (Lancaster County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Buchanan, A. C., Judge (Tazewell County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Budwesky, Carl (Alexandria CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bullington, R. McC. (Alcoholic Beverage Control Board), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Burke, J. A. (Appomattox County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Burnett, Louis R., Dr. (Physical Fitness Program), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Burnley, Seth (Charlottesville CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Burrough, S. Lester (Essex County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Burton, C. G. (Powhatan County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Butler, S. M., Maj. (Aircraft Warning Service), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - C, 1942 December. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - C, 1942 November. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - C, 1942 October. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - C, 1942 September. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - C, 1942 August. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - C, 1942 July. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - C, 1942 June. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - C, 1942 May. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - C, 1942 April. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - C, 1942 March. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - C, 1942 February. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - C, 1942 January. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Caldwell, W. H. (Chesterfield County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Calfee, E. W., Hon. (Pulaski County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Campbell, J. Owen (Botetourt County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Cantwell, A. W. (American Red Cross), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Carper, T. W. (Franklin County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Carper, W. H. (Culpeper County CDC), 1942. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Carrier, Lester R. (Covington CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Curry (Staunton CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Carter, Edward (Prince Edward County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Carter, W. H. (Amherst County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Causey, J. C., Jr. (Suffolk CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Chandler, Desmond B. (Virginia Photographic Association), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Civilian Defense Exectuive Orders, 1942. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cleek, Ernest S. (Bath County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Clifford, William H., Col. (Loudoun County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Closson, George F. (Warwick County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Coburn, W. S. (Augusta County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Cogbill, M. A. (Chesterfield County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Coleman, J. F. (King George County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Coley, Grady (Scott County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Colonna, George B. (Elizabeth City County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Conway, G. F. (Caroline County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Cook, Winfield C. (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cooke, J. Branham (Chief Civilian Air Raid Warning Officer), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Cooley, A. E. (Carroll County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Cowgill, C. H. (Virginia Polytechnic Institute), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Craig, Daley (Augusta County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Cralle, Jefferson B. (King George County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Creasy, C. E. (C and P Telephone), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Creighton, Martha (State Dept. of Education), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Cronly, John (Richmond Office of Civilian Defense), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Crump, Sheppard, Col. (State Property Officer), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - D - Miscellaneous, 1942. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Darden, Colgate W., Governor, 1942. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Davis, A. M. (Buena Vista CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Davis, Edith (State Office of Civilian Defense, 1942. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Davis, James J., Hon. (South Norfolk CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Davis, T. N., Mrs. (Lynchburg), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Deary, Floyd T. (Princess Anne County CDC), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - DeShazor, George S., Jr. (Circuit Court of Warwick County), 1942. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Dickenson, B. L., Hon. (Smyth County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dickenson, W. A. (Cape Charles CDC) 1942. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Division of Purchasing and Printing, 1942. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dodson, W. P. (Virginia Beach CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Donnell, A. T. (West Point CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Doolittle, Clifford (Giles County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Doss, J. S. (Craig County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Dreyfuss, Leonard (East Coast Conference of State Defense Directors), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Drum, Hugh A., General (U. S. Army), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - E - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-December. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - E - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-August. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - E - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-April. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Early, R. N. (Greene County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Eberwine, V. G. (Nansemond County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Edmonds, James E., Major General (Commanding Officer at Fort Lee), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Elder, D. Lane (Hopewell CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Eley, Robert B. (Lee County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Ellett, Tazewell (Henrico County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Elliot, H. M. (Washington County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Elliot, W. Glenn, Major (American Legion), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Elliot, W. W. (Virginia Beach CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Elmore, W. Emory (Brunswick County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Embrey, A. W., Jr. (Fredericksburg Regional Defense Office), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Evans, Frank P., Major (Virginia Retirement System), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - F - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-December. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - F - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-August. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - F - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-April. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Ferguson, Allen (Hopper Paper Company), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Fitzgerald, E. G. (Campbell County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Fitzgerald, H. V., Hon. (Pittsylvania County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Fitzpatrick, W. C., Hon. (Farmville CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Fletcher, Holland K. (St. Paul CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Fletcher, Marshall P., 1942. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Fleming, Alfred T. (National Board of Fire Underwriters), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Ford, F. C. (Radford Regional Civilian Defense Council), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Free, Elmer D. (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Freeman, Douglas S., Dr. (Richmond News Leader) 1942. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 November-December. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-October. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 July-August. (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-June. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 March-April. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-February. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Gallehon, James H. (Bland County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Gamble, Robert H., Rev. (Northampton County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Garber, Walter E. (King William County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Gardner, J. A. (Appalachia CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Garrett, James N., Hon. (Norfolk County CDC), 1942. (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Geddy, Vernon M. (Williamsburg CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Geoghegan, Charles E., Hon. (Mecklenburg County CDC) 1942. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - George, Isaac S. (Maryland Council of Defense), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Gibson, Langhorne, Lt. Comm. (Naval Intelligence Center), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Gibson, Paul (Richmond CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Gill, Tom Irvin (Southern Piedmons Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Gillaspie, J. W., Hon. (Tazewell County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gilmer, W. B. (Dept. of Finance), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Goodwin, J. R., Hon. (Amherst County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Goodwyn, E. E., Brig. Gen. (Virginia Protective Force), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Goolrick, C. O'Connor (Fredericksburg CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Gourley, Susie W. (Fredericksburg Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Gray, Marvin L. (Sussex County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Grant, S. Lee (Winchester CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Green, Jesse C. (Powhatan County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Greene, E. H. (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Greenstein, Harry (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Griffin, H. E. (Buckingham County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 November-December. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-October. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 July-August. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-June. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 March-April. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-February. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Haden, H. A. (Albemarle County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Haden, W. D. (Charlottesville CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Hall, C. M., Hon. (Williamsburg CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Hall, Herbert C. (King and Queen County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Hall, Wilmer (Amherst County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Hall, W. L. (Staunton CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Hallett, S. O. (Nottoway County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Hanrahan, Frank C. (Arlington County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Harkrader, C. J., Hon. (Southwest Virginia Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Harris, George A. (Lunenburg County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Harrison, E. E. (New Kent County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Hart, Alan L., Lt. Col. (Air Raid Warning System), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Hart, R. B. W. (Lynchburg CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Hassinger, L. C. (Bristol CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Hatchett, Joseph M. (Petersburg CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Haynes, William (Northumberland County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Heller, G. E. (Office of Civilian Defense), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Herbert, W. C., Capt. (Richmond CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Hill, William Earl (Brunswick County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Hinckley, John A., Mrs. (Fauquier County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Hobeck, Clarence (Virginia Beach CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Hocutt, John Evans (College of William and Mary), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Hodges, W. T., Dr. (Hampton Roads Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Hodges, Y. M. (Mecklenburg County CDC), 1942. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Holloway, W. J. (Isle of Wight County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Holsinger, Frederick (Highland County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Hooker, John D. (Patrick County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Hopkins, A. C., Rev. (Charlotte County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Hopkins, R. C. (Fredericksburg CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Hudgins, William F. (Princess Anne County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Huff, Clarence W., Jr. (Air Raid Shelter Committee), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Humbert, R. Lee, Mayor (Radford Regional Defence Council), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Hummel, R. S. (Works Project Administration), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hunter, Thomas L. (King George County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Hunter, W. P. (Roanoke CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Hurt, Henry (Pittsylvania County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Hutcheson, John R., Dr. (U.S. Dept. of Agriculture), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - I - Miscellaneous, 1942. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 November-December. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-October. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 July-August. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-June. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 March-April. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-February. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Jackson, C. V. (Wise County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Jackson, J. T. (Virginia Smelting Company), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - James, Ellis N. (Hampton Roads Regional Defense Council), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - James, L. D. (Roanoke CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Janeway, Augustine S., Col. (U. S. Office of Civilian Defense), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Jenson, B. I. (James City County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Johnson, Frank K., Lt. Col. (First Fighter Command), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, S. P. (Prince George County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Jones, Catesby G. (Gloucester County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Jones, Edwin B. (Treasurer of Virginia), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Jordan, Harry B., Lt. Col. (I.S.F.), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Joyner, M. B. (Dendron CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 November-December. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-October. (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 July-August. (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-June. (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 March-April. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1942 January-February. (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Kay, Ashby W. (Goochland County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Kaye, Floyd S. (Bath County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Keay, Roger I. (Norfolk CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Kerns, R. W., Dr. (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - King, Marshall (Fredericksburg CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - King, Percy C. (Surry County CDC), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Kittrell, Flemmie P., Dr. (Hampton Institute), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Kreh, Lewis V. (Third Civilian Defense Region), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Kusterer, Edward L. (Virginia Defense Council), 1942. (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - L - Miscellaneous, 1942 November-December. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - L - Miscellaneous, 1942 September-October. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - L - Miscellaneous, 1942 July-August. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - L - Miscellaneous, 1942 May-June. (Box 8, Folder 4)